(中立区的幻云星三号)
(银河系的和平之星)
还以为这个星球禁用武器
I thought weapons were forbidden on this planet.
何况…
Besides...
你也不会为这片荒土杀我
...I can't believe you'd kill me for a field of empty holes.
这片地是我唯一所有的
It's all I have.
- 你感到很痛苦 - 你怎么知道我的痛苦？
- Your pain runs deep. - What do you know of my pain?
我们一起探索它吧
Let us explore it... together.
每个人都有一种隐藏的苦痛
Each man hides a secret pain.
我们得让它展露，加以解决
It must be exposed and reckoned with.
必须把它从黑暗中逼向光明
It must be dragged from the darkness into the light.
分享你的痛苦 让我分享你的痛苦吧
Share your pain. Share your pain with me.
那么我们就会得到力量
And gain strength from the sharing.
你从哪儿得来这种力量？
Where did you get this power?
它一直在你心中
The power was within you.
现在我感到如释重负
It is as if a weight has been lifted from my heart.
- 我如何报答这个奇？ - 加入我的行列
- How can I repay you? - Join my quest.
- 你在找什么？ - 在找你要找的
- What is it you seek? - What you seek.
自盘古初开 所有人一直在找的东西
What all men have sought since time began.
终极的智慧
The ultimate knowledge.
但我们得先找一艘星船
To find it we need a starship.
星船？幻云星三号没有星船
A starship? There are no starships on Nimbus III.
- 也许我有办法引来一艘 - 怎么引来？
- I have a way to bring one here. - But how?
朋友，你要有信心 跟我们有相同信念的人有很多
Have faith, my friend. There are more of us than you know.
你是瓦肯星人
You're a Vulcan.
(约塞米蒂国家公园) (地球)
(星历8454.1)
"老骨头，你会有一个好玩的假期"
"You'll have a great time on shore leave, Bones."
"你可以轻松愉快地度日"
"You'll be able to relax."
轻松愉快？我快精神崩溃了
You call this relaxing? I'm a nervous wreck.
如此下去，我就会变成疯子
If I'm not careful, I'll end up talking to myself.
你好，舰长
Greetings, Captain.
- 史巴克，你来这儿干嘛？ - 在看你的进度
- Spock, what are you doing here? - I'm monitoring your progress.
我受宠若惊，公园景点这么多 你竟来找我？
I'm flattered, but of all the points of interest here why pick me?
徒手攀爬这个悬崖的纪录 是无人可以打破的
The record for climbing El Capitan is in no danger of being broken.
我爬此峭壁是因我喜欢
I'm doing this because I enjoy it.
遑论爬山最重要的原因
Not to mention the most important reason for climbing a mountain...
因为山就在你面前
Because it's there.
你不知道自己身处险境吧
I do not think you realise the gravity of your situation.
刚好相反 我绝对了解这有多危险
On the contrary, gravity is foremost on my mind.
我要爬山，你去烦老麦好了
I'm trying to make an ascent. Go pester Dr McCoy.
麦医生心情不太好
Dr McCoy is not in the best of moods.
真过分
Goddamn irresponsible!
他简直在玩命
Playing games with life.
关键是要专注 你要与石壁合而为一
Concentration is vital. You must be one with the rock.
若你不再烦着我…
If you don't stop distracting me...
也许"因山就在你面前" 并不是爬山的好理由
Perhaps "because it is there" is not sufficient reason to climb a mountain.
现在我不能不同意你说的
I am hardly in a position to disagree.
老骨头，我们一起吃晚饭好吗？
Hi, Bones. Mind if we drop in for dinner?
(幻云星三号，天堂城)
- 我是戴卡琳 - 对，我们新的罗慕兰代表
- I am Caithlin Dar. - Yes! Our new Romulan representative.
欢迎来到天堂城 堪称银河系和平之星的首都
Welcome to Paradise City, capital of the Planet of Galactic Peace.
我是陶约翰 幻云星三号的星盟代表
I'm St John Talbot, the Federation Representative here on Nimbus III.
这位好伙伴是克林贡领事科德
My charming companion is the Klingon Consul, Korrd.
- 克林贡人是这样打招呼吧 - 请进来
- I expect that's Klingon for hello. - Come in, my dear.
二十年前我们三国政府 同意一起开发这星球
20 years ago, our three governments agreed to develop this planet.
- 一个新时代由此诞生 - 但可惜也很快结束
- A new age was born. - It died a quick death.
被我们骗来此居住的人 互相残杀
The settlers we conned into coming here took to fighting.
我们没收武器 但他们就自制起来
We forbad them weapons, but they fashioned their own.
看来我来得正合时
It appears I've arrived just in time.
别碰那发报机
Get away from that transmitter.
罗慕兰人
Romulan.
地球人
Terran.
克林贡人
Klingon.
- 你们已成为人质 - 人质？
- Consider yourselves my prisoners. - Prisoners?
我们早就是这片荒土的人质
We're already prisoners here on this worthless lump of rock.
- 我们对你有何用处？ - 幻云星三号是一片荒土
- What value could we be to you? - Nimbus III is a worthless lump of rock.
但只有这个地方有你们三人
But it is the only place in the galaxy that has the three of you.
我们的政府会保护我们
Our governments will stop at nothing to ensure our safety.
这就再好不过了
That's exactly what I'm counting on.
企业号试航报告
USS Enterprise, shakedown cruise report.
这艘船定是由猴子建成的
I think this new ship was put together by monkeys.
半数的门开不了 猜谁来收拾烂摊子
Half the doors won't open, and guess whosejob it is to make it right?
混帐
Borgus frat!
舰长说看看它怎样 现在我们知道了
"Let's see what she's got, Scotty." We found out, didn't we?
- 你总有办法修理好它 - 还以为你放假
- I know you'll whip her into shape. - Uhura, I thought you were on leave.
- 该是我们一起放假 - 现在企业号最需要我
- I thought we were going together. - I can't leave her when she needs me.
早料到你会这么说
I had a feeling you would say something like that.
所以我带了晚餐来
So I brought us dinner.
你是世上最善解人意的女人
You're the most understanding woman I know.
红色警报
Red alert.
我刚修理好警报系统的
I just fixed that damn thing!
把它关掉
Turn it off, will you?
红色警报
Red alert.
这是红色警报，企业号请通话
This is a red alert. Enterprise, acknowledge.
这是企业号，请你说明身份
This is Enterprise. Identify yourself.
这是星际舰队 中立区出现七号危机
This is Starfleet. We have a Priority 7 situation in the Neutral Zone.
- 史考特，这是来真的 - 不会吧
- Scotty, this is for real. - They can't be serious!
这艘船破烂不堪 船员又不足够
The ship's in pieces and we've got less than a skeleton crew.
你们知道我们的现况吗？
Starfleet, are you aware of our current status?
知道，请候命和重召船上要员
Yes. Stand by to copy operational orders and recall key personnel.
- 面对现实吧，我们迷路了 - 对，但我们走的速度挺快
- Admit it, we're lost. - Yes, but we're making good time.
- 苏鲁中校，请通话 - 难以置信
- Commander Sulu, come in. - I don't believe this.
要取消休假
Shore leave is cancelled.
- 终于有救了 - 返回原定的地点上船
- Rescued at last. - Return to prearranged coordinates.
- 别说我们迷了路 - 有麻烦吗？
- You can't say we're lost. - Is there a problem?
是的，我们被大风雪所困
Yes. We've been caught in... a blizzard.
什么都看不见，请你指示方向
We can't see a thing. Direct us to the coordinates.
视象器显示现在风和日丽 气温70度
My visual says sunny skies and 70 degrees.
你看，太阳出来了 真是不可思议
Look, the sun has come out. It's a miracle.
放心吧，我会守秘密 现在派飞船去接你们
Don't worry, your secret is safe with me. I'll send the shuttle for you.
乌胡拉，我欠你一个人情
Uhura, I owe you one.
吃晚饭
Come and get it!
老骨头，别再敲了
Bones, knock it off.
我们就在此，快饿死了
We're right here and we're starving.
- 双荚豆？ - 是豆，但不是普通的豆
- Bipodal seeds, Doctor? - Beans, Spock, but no ordinary beans.
是我家传的南方烹调法
These are from an old recipe handed down to me by my father.
若你不愿吃
If you stick your Vulcan nose up at these...
就是对我麦家一种侮辱
you're insulting generations of McCoys.
那我就只好尝尝你煮的豆
In that case I have little choice but to sample your beans.
出奇的美味 里面有一种奇特的调味料
Surprisingly good. It does have a flavouring I'm not familiar with.
- 是秘制的材料 - 还有"秘制材料"吗？
- That's the secret ingredient. - Any more secret ingredient, Bones?
随便喝
Be my guest.
- 你的秘制材料就是酒？ - 田纳西威士忌
- Your secret ingredient is alcohol? - Tennessee whiskey.
威士忌烩豆真刺激 史巴克能吃得下吗？
Bourbon and beans, an explosive combination. Can Spock handle it?
以瓦肯星人的体质 一整碗的白蚁也吃得下
With that Vulcan metabolism, he could eat a bowl of termites.
- 别忘了我有一半是地球人 - 但却看不出来
- Doctor, I am half human. - It certainly doesn't show.
- 谢谢 - 这家伙总是这个模样
- Thank you. - This guy never changes.
我取笑他，他还以为我在赞他
I insult him and he takes it as a compliment.
- 你们俩真懂得气坏我 - 我做了什么？
- You two could drive a man to drink. - What did I do?
人命太宝贵，你不该那样玩命
Human life is far too precious to risk on crazy stunts.
从山崖掉下来会粉身碎骨
You should have been killed when you fell off that mountain.
我有想过这个
It did cross my mind.
但即使掉下来，我也不会死
But even as I fell I knew I wouldn't die.
- 不是只有他才是不死人吗？ - 不是这个原因
- Isn't he the only one who's immortal? - No, it isn't that.
是因为你们在旁，我不会死掉
I knew I wouldn't die because the two of you were with me.
- 我不明白 - 我一直都知道…
- I do not understand. - I've always known...
我会孤独地死去
...I'll die alone.
我会在英烈祠留一个位给你
I'll call Valhalla and reserve a room for you.
我们一起在太空 常令对方生气
All that time in space, getting on each other's nerves...
船员休假去哪儿玩？ 我们三人又聚在一起
So what do we do on shore leave? We spend it together.
- 其他船员有家室 - 我们却没有
- Other people have families. - Other people, not us.
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
我准备烧一粒"棉瓜糖"
I'm preparing to toast a "marsh melon".
真有你的，烧棉瓜糖 你从哪学懂这个？
I'll be damned! A marsh melon. Where did you learn to do that?
我查看过有关 野火会习俗的资料
I have familiarised myself with the customs associated with camping out.
烧完棉瓜糖后又怎样？
What do we do after we toast the marsh melon?
- 把糖吃掉 - 不，我是指吃完糖之后
- We consume them. - No, I mean after that.
我们该一起唱歌
We are required to engage in a ritual known as the sing- along.
多年来我都没坐在 营火旁唱歌了
I haven't sung around the campfire since I was a boy in Iowa.
我们唱什么歌？
What are we going to sing?
- "康普镇赛马"？ - "收拾烦忧"
- "Camptown Races". - "Pack up your troubles".
- 我们要起行了？ - 那只是歌名
- Are we leaving? - It's a song title.
- (里高星七号明月夜) - (划啊划，划你的小船)
- "Moon over Rigel 7". - "Row, row, row your boat".
- 你懂得唱"划你的小船"？ - 我没有研究过这首歌
- Do you know "Row your boat"? - It didn't come up in my research.
歌词很简单
The lyrics are very simple...
(划啊划，划你的小船 慢慢地沿溪流而下)
"Row, row, row your boat gently down the stream."
(快乐地划啊划 人生只是一场梦)
"Merrily, merrily, merrily, merrily, life is but a dream."
我们先唱，然后示意让你加入
The Doctor and I will start off and you jump in.
- 医生？请你领唱 - 我的歌喉不太好
- Doctor, if you please. - Don't say I didn't warn you.
- 史巴克，你为何不唱？ - 我听不明白那些歌词
- Spock, why didn't you jump in? - I cannot comprehend the words.
这只是一首歌，你真没趣 歌词并不重要
It's a song, you green- blooded Vulcan. The words aren't important.
- 只在乎唱个开怀 - 对不起，医生
- You just have a good time singing. - I am sorry, Doctor.
- 我们在唱个开怀吗？ - 我较喜欢复活前的他
- Were we having a good time? - I liked him better before he died.
我们睡觉好了
Let's just get some sleep.
- 舰长？ - 我们在放假，叫我詹姆就行
- Captain... - We're on leave. Call me Jim.
- 詹姆 - 什么事？
- Jim... - Yes, Spock?
人生不是一场梦
Life is not a dream.
- 快睡吧，史巴克 - 是的，舰长
- Go to sleep, Spock. - Yes, Captain.
- 晚安，老骨头 - 晚安，詹姆
- Good night, Bones. - Good night, Jim.
- 晚安，史巴克 - 晚安，医生
- Good night, Spock. - Good night, Doctor.
- 晚安，史巴克 - 晚安，詹姆
- Good night, Spock. - Good night, Jim.
我就是不明白
I don't know. I just don't know.
卡拉舰长，有发现 一个古旧的探空卫星
- 难以把它击落？ - 很困难
好，所有武器由我控制
望远镜
射击太空垃圾 考验不到战士的勇气
我要一个会还击的目标
舰长，新资料 幻云星三号有人被挟持
- 其中一个人质是克林贡人 - 其他人呢？
一个地球人和一个罗慕兰人
星盟定会派船营救他们
把船驶向幻云星三号
我一直都想 和星盟的船舰交锋
别用灯照着我
Get the damn light out of my face.
我们得派出飞船
We had to send the shuttlecraft.
传送器失灵了
The transporter is non- operational.
- 我们接到新的命令 - 我有微型通信器的
- We have received new orders. - I had my communicator.
- 你忘了带在身上 - 我怎么会这样糊涂
- You forgot to take it with you. - I wonder why I did that.
休假取消，快收拾行装
It appears shore leave has been cancelled. Pack out your trash.
"我只要求一艘大船 和有星儿引路"
"All I ask is a tall ship and a star to steer her by."
- 梅维尔 - 梅斯菲尔德
- Melville. - John Masefield.
- 你肯定？ - 我精通古典文学
- Are you sure about that? - I'm well- versed in the classics.
那你为何不懂唱 "划你的小船"？
Then how come you don't know "Row, row, row your boat"?
- 企业号准备接应 - 我们的情况还不错
- Enterprise, you have control. - We're doing just fine.
我只能说新船不及以往的好
All I can say is, they don't make them like they used to.
是你说能在两周内修好此船
You told me you could have this ship operational in two weeks.
看来你给我太多的时间
I think you gave me too much time.
我说过多少次？ 一定要用合适的工具
How many times do I have to tell you? The right tool for the right job.
他从没这么快乐过
I've never seen him happier.
控制室，希望可以上得去
Bridge... I hope.
我要先淋个浴
I could use a shower.
好的
Yes.
- 船上有东西没失灵的吗？ - 我们不能坐此船去执行任务
- Doesn't anything work on this ship? - They can't send us out like this.
- 总部有消息传来 - 用屏幕显示
- Starfleet transmission on line. - Put it on the view screen.
可否静一点？
Can we have a little quiet, please?
可否令影像清晰一点
Can you clear that up?
可否安静一点？
Can we have a little quiet?
- 波布 - 詹姆
- Bob! - Jim!
- 你没穿好制服 - 我正准备去淋浴
- We are dressing informally. - I'm on my way to the shower.
抱歉得取消假期
I apologise for cancelling shore leave.
幻云星三号出现危急的情况
We have a dangerous situation out on Nimbus III.
银河系的和平之星？
On the Planet of Galactic Peace?
恐怖组织占据唯一的殖民地
A terrorist force has captured the only settlement.
他们挟持人质，是克林贡 罗慕兰和星盟的领事
They've taken hostages. The Klingon, the Romulan, the Federation Consuls.
- 企业号未合符规格… - 简直是破烂不堪
- The Enterprise is not up to specs... - The Enterprise is a disaster.
- 这一区定有其他船舰 - 但没有资深的指挥官
- We have ships in the quadrant. - But no experienced commanders.
- 我要寇克掌舵 - 拜托了
- I need Jim Kirk. - Please!
前往幻云星三号评估状况
Proceed to Nimbus III and assess the situation.
避免起冲突
Avoid a confrontation.
最重要的是救回人质
Above all, however, get those hostages back safely.
- 克林贡人已作回应没有？ - 不，但他们一定会
- Have the Klingons responded? - No, but you can bet they will.
- 驶向幻云星三号，苏鲁 - 已设定好航道
- Plot a course for Nimbus III, Mr Sulu. - Course plotted.
恐怕得在路上赶紧修理船舰
I'm afraid the ship's problems will have to be solved en route.
你们得悉力以赴，开始工作
I'm counting on each one of you to give his best. Let's go to work.
詹姆，若你问我，但你没有
Jim, if you ask me, and you haven't...
这不是个好主意 我们定会遇上克林贡人
I think this is a terrible idea. We're bound to bump into the Klingons.
- 他们不喜欢你 - 彼此彼此
- And they don't exactly like you. - The feeling's mutual.
引擎室，我们要全速前进
Engine room, we'll need all the power you can muster, mister.
即使要亲自推船 我们也能打败克林贡人
We'll beat those Klingon devils even if I have to get out and push.
希望不用出此下策
I hope it won't come to that.
- 苏鲁，全速前进 - 遵命，舰长
- All possible speed, Mr Sulu. - Aye, sir.
- 怎么了？ - 我还是喜欢旧的那张椅
- What's the matter? - I miss my old chair.
企业号奉召前往幻云星三号
企业号？是寇克的船
若我能打败寇克…
你就是银河系最英勇的战士
全速前进，成功在望
舰长日志：星历84…
Captain's log: Stardate 84...
(系统故障)
舰长日志：星历84…
Captain's log: Stardate 84...
- 早安，舰长 - 算了
- Good morning, Captain. - Forget it.
- 我们有人质的消息 - 用屏幕显示
- We have the hostage information. - Put it on the screen.
这是星际舰队资料库 核准传送的资料
This is an authorised transmission from the Starfleet memory bank.
- 不是科德上将吧 - 他显然已被放逐
- Not General Korrd! - He's apparently fallen from favour.
他的军事战略 在学堂课程之内
Korrd's military strategies were required learning at the Academy.
他们逼我退休时 希望我的下场比他好
When they put me out to pasture, I hope I fair better than Korrd.
这一定是人质的片段
This must be the hostage tape.
较早前我们向光明兵团投降
A short time ago, we surrendered to the Galactic Army of Light.
现在被他们的首领所挟持
We are now in the protective custody of their leader.
我们跟他们合作就不会受苛待
We will be treated humanely as long as we cooperate.
他要求你速派一艘星船来 商议释放人质的事
He requests that you send a starship to parley for our release at once.
我们无恙 并期望你方立刻作出回应
We are in good health and would appreciate your immediate response.
我抱歉要这么做 但实在迫不得已
I regret this desperate act, but these are desperate times.
我无意伤害这些无辜者 但别以为我不会用武力
I mean no harm to these innocents, but do not put me to the test.
我恳求你方立刻作出回应
I implore you to respond immediately.
怎么了？
What is it?
- 你像见了鬼似的 - 也许是的，舰长
- You look like you've seen a ghost. - Perhaps I have, Captain.
史巴克，怎么了？ 你认识这个瓦肯星人？
Spock, what is it? Do you know this Vulcan?
- 我不肯定 - 但他很面熟？
- I cannot be certain. - But he does seem familiar?
他令我想起年少时的一个朋友
He reminds me of someone I knew in my youth.
- 我不知道你有朋友 - 我不是常想起过去的
- I didn't know you had one. - I do not often think of the past.
- 他令你想起谁？ - 一个青年才俊
- Who does he remind you of? - A gifted young student.
他学识渊博
He possessed a great intelligence.
他该会是另一个伟大的 瓦肯星学者
It was assumed that he would join the great scholars of Vulcan.
- 但他是个革命分子 - 这是什么意思？
- But he was a revolutionary. - What do you mean?
他追求的智慧 为瓦肯星所不容
The knowledge he sought was forbidden by Vulcan belief.
- 不容？ - 他摒弃具逻辑性的教养
- Forbidden? - He rejected his logical upbringing.
崇尚我们祖先那种野性的狂热
He embraced the animal passions of our ancestors.
他相信求自知的关键是情感 而不是逻辑
He believed the key to self- knowledge was emotion... not logic.
试想像一下 一个多情的瓦肯星人
Imagine that, a passionate Vulcan.
当他鼓励别人加入其行列 就被放逐到异地
When he encouraged others to follow him, he was banished from Vulcan.
真有意思
Fascinating.
- 请舰长到控制室 - 我来了
- Captain to the bridge. - On my way.
- 史巴克？ - 来了，舰长
- Spock? - Coming, Captain.
- 正驶近幻云星三号 - 标准轨迹，苏鲁
- Approaching Nimbus III. - Standard orbit, Mr Sulu.
天堂城要求我方表明来意
Paradise City is demanding to know our intentions.
以静电干扰作回覆 让他们以为我们机件故障
Respond with static. Let them think we're having difficulty.
天堂城 我们收不清楚你的信息
Paradise City, we are barely receiving your transmission.
- 传送室情况如何？ - 仍然未能操作
- Transporter room, status. - Transporter is still inoperative.
即使找到人质 也不能传送他们过来
If we could lock on to the hostages, we couldn't beam them up.
- 我们得亲自救他们走 - 克林贡船舰正逼近
- We'll have to get them out ourselves. - Klingon vessel approaching.
猛禽号，1.9个小时后就相遇
Bird of Prey. 1.9 hours till her weapons are in range.
可恶，走吧
Damn! Let's go.
- =字幕:CHD720P代刻=-
他们的扫瞄设备古老 但甚管用
Their scanning equipment is primitive, but effective.
- 在方位856.3降落 - 那离城市很远
- Land at coordinate 856.3. - That's far from the city.
- 我们得避开侦察 - 苏鲁，开船去
- We cannot risk detection. - Mr Sulu, execute.
- 这是企业号 - 星际舰队的船
- This is the starship Enterprise. - A Federation starship.
这是契可夫舰长 你触犯了我们条约的规定
This is Captain Pavel Chekov. You are in violation of our treaty.
立刻释放人质，否则后果自负
Release your hostages at once or suffer the consequences.
别逗我笑了，什么后果？
Your threats amuse me. What consequences?
一艘克林贡船会在 一小时后飞到来
A Klingon warship will arrive within the hour.
- 克林贡人会大怒 - 他们会毁掉这星球
- The Klingons will be quite angry. - They are likely to destroy the planet.
那我幸得有你的星船保护
Then it is fortunate I have you and your starship to protect me.
现在我命令你们速到我这里来
You and your first officer are to beam down to my coordinates.
我们乐意来 但得先作好一些准备
We will be happy to beam down, but we must have certain assurances.
驶去天堂城要1.2个小时
At foot speed the journey to the city will take 1.2 hours.
我们没这么多时间
We don't have 1.2 hours.
且慢…行了 我们得引起他们的注意
Wait a minute... Perfect! We'll have to get their attention.
那是什么？
What's that?
她赤裸裸的吗？
Is she naked?
各位好
Hello, boys.
我一直都渴望 能以歌声俘虏人心
I've always wanted to play to a captive audience.
- 史巴克，你要与马合一 - 是的，舰长
- Spock, be one with the horse. - Yes, Captain.
开闸，这是我们的侦察队
Open the gate. It's our lookout party.
星盟士兵在后面，快关闸
Federation soldiers are right behind us. Close the gate.
他们去哪？
Where are they going?
- 史巴克… - 等一下，我在作扫瞄
- Spock... - Hold your horse, I'm scanning.
人质在那座建筑物里面
The hostages are being held in that structure.
加利里奥，开始行动
Galileo, start your run.
用死光枪击晕敌人 苏鲁射破那盏灯
Phasers on stun. Sulu, take out that light.
- 怎么回事？ - 快投降，你们正遇袭
- What's going on? - Surrender, you are under attack.
- 我不是要有死伤 - 慢着，你回来
- It wasn't bloodshed I wanted. - Wait! Come back.
- 乌胡拉，快下来 - 知道了，来了
- Uhura, come on down. - Roger, coming in.
幻云星三号以野生动物著名 也是上佳的钓鱼地点
Nimbus III is famous for its wildlife, and the fishing is terrific!
星盟提供方便的资助 助你到那儿去
Easy financing through Federation Federal can take you there.
- 谢天谢地 - 请你们合作
- Thank God. - Please cooperate.
交出武器
Hand over your weapons.
做得好，朋友们
Well done, my friends.
你是谁？
Qual se tu?
史巴克？
Spock!
史巴克，是我
Spock, it's me.
是西波克，你终于找到我了
It's Sybok. You've finally caught up with me.
你不是有话跟我说吗？
Don't you have anything to say to me?
你因触犯中立区条约 十七条规定而被捕
You are under arrest for 17 violations of the Neutral Zone Treaty.
- 你培养到一点幽默感了 - 我不是要逗你笑
- You've developed a sense of humour. - I did not intend to amuse you.
你犯的是严重罪行 但若你立刻投降…
These are serious charges. However, if you surrender now...
对不起 我还没触犯完所有规定
I'm sorry, Spock, I'm not through violating the Neutral Zone Treaty.
现在才只是开始 我接着要犯的罪是…
In fact, I'm just getting started. For my next violation...
我要偷一样东西
I intend to steal something.
一样很大的东西
Something very big.
你的星船
Your starship.
你做这一切 是为了抢我的星船？
You staged all this to get your hands on my ship?
- 你是谁？ - 寇克舰长
- Who are you? - Captain James T. Kirk.
我以为契可夫舰长… 我明白了，你很聪明
I thought Captain Chekov... I see... very clever, Captain.
我再给你一个机会 加入我的行列
Spock, you have been given a second chance to join me.
- 我是星际舰队的官员 - 当然了
- I am a Starfleet officer. - Of course.
那我就不用你帮忙 抢走这艘星船
Of course. Then I'll take the ship without your help.
- 飞船正在途中 - 猛禽号的位置呢？
- Shuttle en route. - Position of Bird of Prey?
正逼近
Closing!
估计射程在八千星里
秘密行动 把冲力减至四分之一水平
准备隐形，启动隐形设备
- 猛禽号一定隐了形 - 开防护罩
- The Bird of Prey must have cloaked. - Raise shields.
- 飞船呢？ - 快动手，开动红色警报
- The shuttle? - Do it. Go to red alert.
我们一占据你的船舰 我们就会带追随者来
Once we control your vessel, we'll bring up our followers.
克林贡人就在附近 能够上船已算走运
The Klingons are out there. We'll be lucky to make it to the ship.
这是企业号，红色警报
This is Enterprise, red alert.
猛禽号正逼近，已开了防护罩
Bird of Prey approaching. Raising shields.
快找安全的船坞
Find a safe harbour.
不行
No!
不作回覆，继续沿此航道前行
No reply. Remain on course.
听着，要让飞船进入船坞
Listen to me. In order for this craft to enter the landing bay...
企业号得关上防护罩 启动牵引光波
Enterprise must lower the shields and activate the tractor beam.
- 重开防护罩要… - 15.5秒
- To re- raise the shields will take... - 15.5 seconds.
在这段时间足让敌人猛烈轰击
An eternity, during which we'll be vulnerable to attack.
他说得对，若我的人不见了 他们会施袭
He speaks the truth. If my people are cloaked, then they intend to strike.
- 我们不能回头 - 让我们想办法
- We cannot turn back. - Let me do something.
好，做你该做的就行了
Very well, do what you must, but no more.
企业号，这是寇克
Enterprise, this is Kirk.
寇克，他在飞船上 快改攻击航道
明白你方处境 我们无法返回星球
Understand your situation. Are unable to return to planet.
准备采取紧急降落…B计划
Stand by to execute emergency landing plan... B.
- 紧急降落B计划？ - B计划就是B计划
- Emergency landing plan B? - B as in barricade.
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
为了令防护罩迅速开关 我们得先启动牵引光波
In order to lower and raise the shields quickly, we'll forego the tractor beam.
我们要人手驾驶飞船回去
We'll fly her in manually.
- 你常这样做？ - 这是首次尝试
- How often have you done this? - Actually, it's my first attempt.
他技术了得…是真的
He's good... really.
史考特，开船坞门
Scotty, open bay doors.
准备解除隐形设备，发射炮弹
史考特，关上防护罩
Scotty, lower shields.
关上防护罩
Lowering shields.
- 猛禽号的位置是105.2 - 去吧，苏鲁
- Bird of Prey bearing 105.2. - Go, Sulu.
他们进来了
They're in.
- 瞄准企业号 - 已瞄准目标
- 光速飞行 - 发射
Warp speed now!
追踪其航道
他果然了得
我们得立刻改变航道
We must change course at once.
我带你去控制室
I'll take you to the bridge.
把枪捡起来
Pick it up.
西波克
Sybok...
你立刻投降
You must surrender.
不
No!
- 除非你杀了我 - 开枪
- You must kill me. - Shoot him!
有一刻…我以为你真的会下手
For a moment... I thought you might actually do it.
把他跟寇克舰长一起关起来
Put him in the brig with Captain Kirk.
史巴克，你陪我去控制室吧
Spock, you will accompany me to the bridge?
不，我不去
No... I will not.
你知道我是对的
You know I'm right.
那你得跟他们一起成为囚犯
Then you must join them.
- 这两个人会有用处 - 让我们独处一会
- These two will be useful. - Give us a moment alone.
别害怕
Don't be afraid.
混帐，史巴克，你出卖了我们
Goddamn it, Spock. You betrayed us all.
我不奢望你原谅我
I do not expect you to forgive me.
- 我得揍扁你 - 随你喜欢
- I ought to knock you on your ass. - If you think it would help.
- 要我抓住他吗？ - 别插嘴…为什么？
- You want me to hold him? - Stay out of this... Why?
- 你只需开枪就是了 - 那么西波克会死掉
- All you had to do was pull the trigger. - Then Sybok would be dead.
- 我命令你保护企业号 - 和杀掉亲兄弟
- I ordered you to defend your ship. - And kill my brother.
- 虽同是瓦肯星人… - 他也是萨雷克的儿子
- A fellow Vulcan is not a... - Sybok also is a son of Sarek.
他是你的亲兄弟？你说谎
He's your brother brother? You made that up.
- 我没有 - 你没有兄弟
- I did not. - You don't have a brother.
- 技术上而言是没有 - 听见吗？
- Technically I don't have a brother. - See?
- 他是我半个哥哥 - 我得先坐下来
- I have a half- brother. - I've got to sit down.
你和他是同父异母的兄弟？
You and Sybok have the same father but different mothers?
他母亲是瓦肯公主 但我们俩一起长大
Sybok's mother was a Vulcan princess, but we were raised as brothers.
- 你为何没提过这件事？ - 这是私事
- Why didn't you tell us this before? - It is a personal matter.
- 抱歉没告诉你 - 这就一笔勾销了，抱歉？
- For that I am sorry. - That makes everything all right. Sorry!
史巴克要是杀你也下不了手
Spock could no more kill his own brother than he could kill you.
且他早已在囚室 何况我们面前有更大的难题
He's already in the brig. Besides, we've got bigger problems to deal with.
例如我们怎么脱身
Like how do we get out of here.
但我还得说你总令我意想不到
I'll say one thing, you never cease to amaze me.
我也有同感
Nor I myself.
- 我开始担忧 - 没事，西波克会解释一切
- I was beginning to worry. - It's all right. Sybok will explain.
- 你在做什么？ - 设定新的航道
- What are you doing? - Plotting our new course.
你没这权力
You have no authority.
- 怎么了？ - 契可夫，听他说的
- What's going on here? - Pavel, listen to this man.
- 我不明白 - 每个人都有一种隐藏的苦痛
- I don't understand. - Each of us hides a secret pain.
和我分享痛苦，从中取得力量
Share yours with me and gain strength from the sharing.
没用
Useless.
不智
Unwise.
你该警告我…一定有办法脱身
You could have warned me. There's got to be a way out.
- 这囚室异常坚固 - 你怎么知道？
- This new brig is escape- proof. - How do you know?
设计者用最聪明的人作试验
The designers tested it using the most intelligent person they could find.
- 他也逃不了 - 这个人有尖耳朵的？
- He failed to escape. - Did this person have pointed ears?
且总能令他的同僚遇上麻烦
And an unerring capacity for getting his shipmates into trouble?
他确实有尖耳朵
He did have pointed ears.
- 沿新航道前进，用七段光速 - 那个在6.7个小时后到达
- Following new course. Warp 7. - Arrival in 6.7 hours at present speed.
现在航行顺利 我就宣布此行的目的
Now that we're underway, I'll announce my intentions to the rest of the ship.
企业号英勇的船员 想想存在的问题
Brave crew of the starship Enterprise, consider the questions of existence.
这些问题早在人类 凝望星儿和梦想时出现
Questions that man has asked since he first gazed at the stars and dreamed.
我瓦肯星的祖先为情感所操控
My Vulcan ancestors were ruled by their emotions.
他们以心去感受事物
They felt with their hearts.
以至诚去交合 他们相信自己的心意
They made love with their hearts. They believed with their hearts.
且相信有一个地方 能解开这一切的疑问
And they believed in a place where these questions would be answered.
现代教条指 这个地方只是一个神话
Modern dogma tells us this place is a myth.
一个由异教徒捏造出来的传说
A fantasy concocted by pagans.
这不是一个传说
It is no fantasy.
我告诉你…它确实存在
I tell you... it exists.
我的兄弟们，我们被挑选出来
My brothers, we have been chosen -
作出历来最伟大的冒险
- to undertake the greatest adventure of all time.
探索"香格里拉"
The discovery of Sha Ka Ree.
他有可能找到香格里拉吗？ 那是他离开瓦肯星的原因？
Is it possible he's found Sha Ka Ree, the reason he left Vulcan?
我们的目的地是香格里拉
Our destination is the planet Sha Ka Ree.
它位于大屏障以外
It lies beyond the Great Barrier...
银河系的中心
... at the centre of the galaxy.
- 银河系的中心？ - 传说香格里拉所在之地
- The centre of the galaxy? - Where it is fabled to exist.
没有船舰能到达银河系的中心
The centre of the galaxy can't be reached by any ship.
西波克是我认识的人中 最有智慧的
Sybok possessed the keenest intellect I've ever known.
当我取回星船 而西波克又在此
When I get the ship back, and Sybok is in here...
你可以为香格里拉 争论个面红耳赤
you can debate Sha Ka Ree until you're green in the face.
你究竟站不站在我这一方
You're either with me or you're not.
- 我在这儿，舰长 - 答得含糊
- I am here, Captain. - That's a little vague, Spock.
什么声音？
What's that noise?
是古老的通信方法 摩尔斯电码
It's a primitive form of communication known as Morse code.
对，很久没用这个了 那是一个S
You're right. I'm out of practice. That's an S.
- T - A
- T... - A...
N…D，这个字完了
N... D... End of word.
- 是"退"字 - 另一个字
- Stand. - New word.
B…A
B... A...
C…K
C... K...
- "后" - 是"退后"
- Back. - Stand back!
你们站在这干嘛？我是来劫狱
What are you standing around for? This is a jailbreak.
这三个人情同手足 对付他们是一个挑战
These three are strong. This will be quite a challenge.
我们得找他们回来
We've got to find them.
- 现在谁都信不过 - 我们可以发求救信号
- We can't trust anyone. - We can send a distress signal.
观察室有紧急传信设备
There is an emergency sending apparatus in the observation room.
可以沿三号涡轮槽到那儿去
You might be able to reach it by means of turbo- shaft 3.
- 爬上去既费时又危险 - 有些人就是爱冒险
- It's a long and dangerous climb. - Some of us get off on that.
快修好传送器和联络拯救船
Get the transporter working and contact a rescue ship.
- 哪儿通去涡轮槽？ - 沿这通道去，再转右
- Which way to the turbo- shaft? - Down that tunnel and turn right.
- 你一定看见 - 史考特，你真棒
- You can't miss it. - Mr Scott, you're amazing.
我对此船了如指掌
I know this ship like the back of my hand.
- 看来要做一番运动 - 又或是会心脏病发
- We'll get a good workout. - Yeah, or a heart attack.
快送史考特去医疗室
Get Mr Scott to sick bay.
还要爬很久很久
This is going to take me forever.
史巴克呢？
Where's Spock?
我有更快捷的方法
I believe I've found a faster way.
- 老骨头？ - 我等下一回吧
- Bones? - I'll wait for the next car.
我们共同进退
We're not splitting up.
- 我们太重了 - 一定是因吃了太多棉瓜糖
- We're too heavy. - It must be the marsh melons.
- 史巴克，开推进器 - 我控制不了它们
- Spock, the booster rockets. - I can't control their power.
开推进器
Fire the rockets.
舰长，请你下来
Captain, please come back down.
刹掣
Hit the brakes.
- 比要去的层数高了一层 - 人谁无错
- I overshot the mark by one level. - Nobody's perfect.
史巴克
Spock.
紧急频道开启
Emergency channel open.
区内有人吗？我是寇克舰长
To anyone within range, this is Captain James T. Kirk.
若听到我说的，请通话
If you read me, acknowledge.
请通话
Acknowledge.
这是舰队司令，我们听见你的
This is Starfleet Command, we read you. Over.
一个恐怖组织骑劫了我们的船
A hostile force has taken control of our vessel.
我们的方位是000.2 要求紧急救援
Our coordinates are 000.2. Request emergency assistance.
明白了，企业号 我们立刻派救援船去
Understood Enterprise, we are dispatching a rescue ship immediately.
把航道设定为000.2
但这样做 我们也会驶向大屏障
寇克去哪，我们就去哪
- 相信有人已接到你的信息 - 难道我们坐以待毙吗？
- I trust your message was received. - You can't expect us to stand by.
你所害怕的是不明的东西
What you fear is the unknown.
地球人曾相信世界是平直的
The people of your planet once believed their world was flat.
哥伦布证明地球是圆的
Columbus proved it was round.
有说音障是不可以打破的 但却不然
They said the sound barrier could never be broken. It was broken.
有说超光速飞行是不能实现的
They said warp speed could not be achieved.
大屏障是世人恐惧感的 最大体现
The Great Barrier is the ultimate expression of this universal fear.
也让每个人心存更大的畏惧
It is an extension of personal fear.
寇克舰长，我极需要你的谅解
Captain Kirk, I so much want your understanding.
我需要你的尊重 你害怕听我的心底话？
I want your respect. Are you afraid to hear me out?
- 我什么都不怕 - 你们在外面等
- I'm afraid of nothing. - Wait outside.
你一定有很多问题
I'm sure you have many questions.
在银河系芸芸的星球中
Here, amidst the stars of our own galaxy...
我们得一起寻找答案
we shall seek the answers together.
别紧张，史考特，你安全无恙了
Easy, Scotty. You're back with us.
我梦见一个疯子骑劫了企业号
I dreamt that a madman had taken over the Enterprise.
- 他不是疯子 - 不是？
- He's not a madman. - He's not?
西波克让我们面对 我们一直不敢表达的情感
Sybok has put us in touch with feelings we've always been afraid to express.
- 我要去修理传送器 - 史考特
- I have to get to the transporter. - Scotty!
- 我有很多话要跟你说 - 待我精神好一点再说吧
- There's so much I want to tell you. - Wait till I'm a wee bit stronger.
现在我该应付不来
I don't think I could take it in my present condition... or yours.
你也该一样
香格里拉，万物之始
Sha Ka Ree. The Source.
天堂
Heaven.
伊甸，随你怎么叫它
Eden. Call it what you will.
克林贡人称之为古伊图
The Klingons call it Qui Tu.
罗慕兰人称之为窝塔和 安多里安人语的更难发音
The Romulans, Vorta Vor. In Andorian it is unpronounceable.
但每个民族都有 这个相同的梦想
Still, every culture shares this common dream.
一个万物由它而始的地方 这快将成为一个事实
A place from which creation sprang. For us it will soon be reality.
我只知道我成为了 自己船上的俘虏
My only reality is that I'm a prisoner on my own ship.
你有什么能力控制 我部下的思想？
What is this power you have to control the minds of my crew?
我不控制别人的思想 是解开他们的心锁
I don't control minds... I free them.
怎么解？
How?
令人面对自己的苦痛 从中取得力量
By making you face your pain and draw strength from it.
取得那力量后，你就无所畏惧
Once that's done, fear cannot stop you.
听起来像是洗脑
It sounds like brainwashing to me.
你的苦痛很大
Your pain is the deepest of all.
我能够感受得到？你能够吗？
I can feel it, can't you?
里安纳
Leonard.
这是你耍的把戏
This is some kind of trick.
里安纳
Leonard.
爸爸？天，别这样对我
Father? My God! Don't do this to me.
里安纳
Leonard.
我就在此和你一起，爸爸
I'm here. I'm with you, Dad.
痛苦，终止这种痛苦
The pain. Stop the pain.
我已竭尽所能，你得撑下去
I've done everything I can do. You've got to hang on.
我忍受不了这种痛苦
I can't stand the pain.
帮助我
Help me.
我已想尽办法，但仍救不了他
All my knowledge and I can't save him.
你已尽力而为 维生系统可保住他的命
You've done all you can. The support system will keep him alive.
- 这算是生存吗？ - 孩子…
- You call this alive? - Son...
- 解除我的痛苦吧 - 我下不了手，爸爸
- Release me. - I can't do that, Dad.
但我怎么能够看着他受苦？
But how can I watch him suffer like this?
你是医生
You're a doctor.
我是他的儿子
I'm his son.
你为何这样做？
Why did you do it?
让他保有尊严
To preserve his dignity.
- 这不是最糟的，对吗？ - 不是
- That wasn't the worst of it, was it? - No!
分享你的痛苦吧
Share it.
不久后就有医治的良方 能医好他的良方
Not long after, they found a cure. A goddamn cure.
- 若你没下手，他该仍在生 - 我是免他受苦
- If you didn't kill him, he'd have lived. - I released him!
- 你做你以为是对的事 - 是的，不是
- You did what you thought was right. - Yes! No!
解开这个心锁
Release this pain!
这种苦痛折磨了你很多年
This pain has poisoned your soul for a long time.
现在你已踏出第一步
Now you've taken the first step.
其余的路，我们一起走吧
The other steps we'll take together.
每个人都有其独有的苦痛
Each man's pain is unique.
我没有苦痛
I hide no pain.
- 我比你更了解你自己 - 是吗？
- I know you better than that. - Do you?
- 史巴克，不要 - 没事的，舰长
- Spock, don't. - It's all right, Captain.
来吧
Proceed.
- 这是什么？ - 这是我出世的情形
- What is this? - I believe we are witnessing my birth.
萨雷克，你的儿子
Sarek, your son.
太像地球人了
So human.
史巴克？
Spock?
- 你对我的朋友做过什么？ - 没什么，这是他们的经历
- What have you done to my friends? - Nothing. This is who they are.
- 你不知道吗？ - 我不知道
- Didn't you know that? - No, I didn't.
- 现在看看你的吧 - 不，我不要看
- Now learn something about yourself. - No, I refuse.
- 詹姆，试试开明一点 - 为什么要开明？
- Jim, try to be open about this. - About what?
为了我错误的人生决定？ 为了我以往走错了的路？
How I made wrong choices in my life? Turning left instead of right?
我不需要西波克 让我细看自己的弱点
I don't need Sybok to take me on a tour of my weaknesses.
被一个骗子洗脑
To be brainwashed by a conman!
- 这骗子了结我的痛苦 - 用魔术棒把痛苦挥走？
- This conman took away my pain. - With the wave of a magic wand?
我们的经历是挥之不去的
The things we carry with us make us who we are.
没有这一切，我们就会迷失
If we lose them, we lose ourselves.
我不要别人了结我的痛苦 我需要它
I don't want my pain taken away. I need my pain.
舰长，你留在此 史巴克、麦医生跟我来
Captain, you remain here. Spock, Dr McCoy, come with me.
- 史巴克？ - 我不跟你走
- Spock? - I cannot go with you.
- 为什么？ - 我属于这儿
- Why not? - I belong here.
- 我不明白 - 西波克
- I don't understand. - Sybok...
你是我哥哥，但你不了解我
You are my brother, but you do not know me.
我不是多年前被你舍弃的男孩
I am not the outcast boy you left behind many years ago.
我已找到自我和所属的地方 而且知道自己是谁
I found myself and my place, and I know who I am.
我不能跟你走
I cannot go with you.
我也不会跟你走
You'd better count me out, too.
- 那我们在世界的另一面再见 - 且慢
- Then I'll see you on the other side. - Wait!
我们永远不能穿越大屏障
We'll never make it through the Great Barrier.
若然成功 那你就会相信我所言非虚？
If we do, will that convince you that my vision was true?
都是上帝给我的梦想 他在另一面等我们
It was given to me by God. He waits for us on the other side.
你是疯的
You are mad.
是吗？
Am I?
这个自有分晓
We'll see.
没有船舰可以穿越大屏障
They say no ship can survive this.
错了，危险只是一种假象
They're wrong. Danger is an illusion.
所有设备没有读数显示
We have no instrument readings.
- 苏鲁先生，全速前进 - 全速前进
- Mr Sulu, full ahead. - Full ahead, aye.
- 有此可能吗？ - 太神奇了
- Is it possible? - Fascinating.
我们在发梦吗？
Are we dreaming?
若然是的话 那么人生就是一场梦
If we are, then life is a dream.
(勇闯无人踏过之境)
有读数显示了
Instruments are back on line.
难以置信
Incredible.
这星球发放一种 我前所未见的能量
There is a power source emanating from the planet like nothing I've seen.
- 是香格里拉 - 古伊图
- Sha Ka Ree. - Qui Tu.
窝塔和
Vorta Vor.
伊甸
Eden.
- 这艘船的… - 这艘船需要它的舰长
- About the ship... - The ship needs its captain.
- 没有特别的条件？ - 毫无条件
- No special conditions? - No conditions.
- 我可以叫大家掉头 - 不，你也需要知道真相
- I could turn us around. - No, you too must know.
若然要这么做 那就按本子办事
Well, if we're going to do it, we're going to do it by the book.
按标准轨迹前行 让飞船准备妥当
Standard orbital approach. Alert the shuttlecraft to stand by.
西波克、史巴克、老麦跟我来 其他人留在船上
Sybok, Spock, McCoy, come with me. The rest of you remain on board.
先让我了解我们身处什么境地
Until I determine what we're dealing with.
别呆站在那儿，上帝很忙碌的
Don't just stand there, God's a busy man.
飞船不受我的控制
I am no longer in control of the craft.
好吧，依你的方法做
All right, we'll play it your way.
真美丽，看这片天和地
It's amazing. The land. The sky.
一如我所料的
Just as I knew it would be.
- 你得看这个 - 我没时间
- You have to see this. - I don't have time.
舰长要我修理好传送器
The Captain told me to get the transporter working.
我们远道而来
We have travelled far.
乘星船来此
By starship.
企业号，这是寇克
Enterprise, this is Kirk.
我们有…
We have...
西波克
Sybok.
也许…
Perhaps...
四位勇者，欢迎到来
Brave souls, welcome.
这是上帝的声音吗？
Is this the voice of God?
一把声音，无数的脸孔
One voice, many faces.
这样更符合你所预期的吗？
Does this better suit your expectations?
- 你是谁？ - 我就是我
- Qual se tu? - It is I.
你们的旅程一定相当艰辛
Your journey could not have been an easy one.
对，我们得穿越大屏障
It was not. We had to breach the Barrier.
了不起 你们是首批找到我的人
Magnificent. You are the first to find me.
- 我们要寻找你无穷的智慧 - 你们如何穿越大屏障
- We sought only your infinite wisdom. - How did you breach the Barrier?
- 乘星船 - 这艘星船
- With a starship. - This starship...
可以把我的智慧带到 大屏障以外的地方吗？
Could it carry my wisdom beyond the Barrier?
- 可以的 - 那我就要用上它
- It could, yes. - Then I shall make use of it.
- 那会成为你的战车 - 请恕我打岔
- It will be your chariot. - Excuse me...
- 那我就可以无远弗届 - 我想问一个问题
- I will reach every corner of creation. - I'd like to ask a question.
- 上帝要星船来做什么？ - 把船驶近一点
- What does God need with a starship? - Bring the ship closer.
上帝要星船来做什么？
What does God need with a starship?
- 你在做什么？ - 在问问题
- What are you doing? - Asking a question.
- 这个家伙是谁？ - 你不知道？你不是上帝吗？
- Who is this creature? - Don't you know? Aren't you God?
- 他有所怀疑 - 你怀疑我？
- He has his doubts. - You doubt me?
- 我要证明 - 你不可以叫上帝证明身份
- I seek proof. - You don't ask the Almighty for his ID.
这就是你要的证明
Then here is the proof you seek.
- 上帝为何生气？ - 你为何这么做？
- Why is God angry? - Why have you done this?
- 他怀疑我 - 你没有回答他的问题
- He doubts me. - You have not answered his question.
上帝要星船来做什么？
What does God need with a starship?
你也怀疑我？
Do you doubt me?
我不相信任何 以伤害人为乐的神
I doubt any god who inflicts pain for his own pleasure.
住手，香格里拉的神 是不会这样做的
Stop! The god of Sha Ka Ree would not do this.
香格里拉？那是你的幻想
Sha Ka Ree? A vision you created.
我被困在这个地方无限年了
An eternity I've been imprisoned in this place.
我一定要那艘星船
The ship. I must have the ship.
现在快交出星船
Now... give me what I want.
西波克
Sybok...
这不是香格里拉的神 或是其他神灵
This is not the god of Sha Ka Ree, or any other god.
我不明白，快显露你的真面目
I don't understand. Reveal yourself to me.
怎么了？你不喜欢这张脸？
What's wrong? Don't you like this face?
我有无数的脸 但这张脸最适合你
I have so many, but this one suits you best.
不可能的
No, it's not possible.
快把船驶过来 否则我就杀掉你
Bring me the ship or I will destroy you.
- 星船 - 把它驶过来
- The ship. - Bring it closer...
那我就可以与它遨游太空
...so that I might join with it.
快依我的话去做 否则这些人…
Do it, or watch these puny things -
就会死得很惨
- die horribly.
- 我做错了什么？ - 企业号，听好
- What have I done? - Enterprise, listen carefully.
这是我的错，我的自大 我的虚荣心
This is my doing. This is my arrogance. My vanity.
- 西波克，我们得想办法… - 不，你们快逃命
- Sybok, we must find a way... - No, save yourselves.
原谅我，弟弟
Forgive me, brother.
我发现你内心很痛苦
I couldn't help but notice your pain.
是莫大的痛苦，与我分享吧
It runs deep. Share it with me.
- 企业号，准备好没有？ - 已装好飞弹
- Enterprise, are you ready? - Torpedo armed.
- 正向你的位置发射 - 快动手？
- We're firing on your position. - Send it down now!
快逃
Run!
西波克
Sybok...
我们走吧
Let's get out of here.
苏鲁，我失去他们的踪迹
Sulu, I've lost them.
史巴克，快开船
Spock, get us out of here.
推进器失灵
Thrusters are inoperative.
史考特，求你告诉我 传送器已修妥
Mr Scott, please tell me the transporter is working.
我可以传送两人上船
I might be able to beam up two of you.
- 快接史巴克和麦医生走 - 且慢
- Beam up Spock and Dr McCoy now. - Just a damn minute!
快救舰长
Bring up the Captain.
- 不可以弃他不顾 - 你冷静一点
- We can't just leave Jim down there. - Get a grip on yourself. Status report.
克林贡舰长想说他要的条件
The Klingon captain wishes to name his terms.
这是克林贡帝国的卡拉舰长
This is Captain Klaa of the Klingon Empire.
休想动武，我会把你们杀光
Do not attempt to arm your weapons or I will destroy you.
你们还没死掉，只因叛徒寇克
You are alive for a single reason: The renegade James T. Kirk.
快交他出来 那我就饶你们的狗命
Hand him over and I will spare your lives.
- 准备好接他上船了 - 寇克舰长不在
- I'm ready to beam him aboard. - Captain Kirk is not among us.
- 你说谎 - 瓦肯星人是不懂说谎的
- You lie. - Vulcans are incapable of lying.
- 舰长在下面的星球 - 那快说方位
- Captain Kirk is on the planet below. - Then give me his coordinates.
- 我需要你的帮忙？ - 我的帮忙？
- I am in need of your assistance. - My assistance?
- 你是他的上司 - 我只是一个老糊涂
- You are his superior officer. - I am a foolish old man.
别嗦，你得尽力一试
Damn you, sir. You will try.
克林贡指挥官，有人想跟你谈
Klingon commander, someone wishes to speak with you.
你们这班混蛋想抓的是我
So it's me you want, you bastards.
那还等什么？
What are you waiting for?
释放他
Release him.
我的部下有话要跟你说
My junior officer has something he wants to say to you.
我很…抱歉
I... apologise.
我向你方施袭 未经我国政府批准
The attack upon your vessel was not authorised by my government.
现在让我介绍我们新的炮手
Now, may I present our new gunner.
- 史巴克 - 欢迎你上船，舰长
- Spock! - Welcome aboard, Captain.
我还以为性命不保
I thought I was going to die.
不可能，你从不孤单无助
Not possible, you were never alone.
拜托，别在克林贡人面前失仪
Please, Captain, not in front of the Klingons.
想喝一口威士忌吗？
Would you care for a wee nip of Scotch whiskey?
没想过我会与克林贡人共饮
I never thought I'd be drinking with a Klingon.
- 你们在密谈什么？ - 谈我们取得的成果
- What are you two conspiring about? - About the progress we've made.
她的肌肉很结实
She has wonderful muscles.
两位在思索宇宙的奥秘？
Cosmic thoughts, gentlemen?
我们在想… 上帝究竟存不存在？
We were speculating... Is God really out there?
也许他不在外面
Maybe he's not out there.
也许他就在我们心里
Maybe he's right here in the human heart.
- 史巴克？ - 我在想西波克
- Spock? - I was thinking of Sybok.
- 我失去一个兄弟 - 没错
- I have lost a brother. - Yes.
我也曾失去一个兄弟
I lost a brother, once.
幸好他能重回我身边
I was lucky. I got him back.
是你说我们这种人没家庭的
I thought you said men like us don't have families.
我错了
I was wrong.
你究竟会不会弹一首歌？
Are you just going to pluck that thing, or are you going to play something?
(划啊划，划你的小船)
Row, row, row your boat
(慢慢地沿溪流而下)
gently down the stream
(快乐地划啊划)
merrily, merrily, merrily, merrily